Hello
مرحبا
and welcome back to our English listening practice.
ومرحبا بعودتنا إلى ممارسة الاستماع إلى اللغة الإنجليزية.
How are you today?
كيف حالك اليوم؟
I hope you're doing well.
آمل أن تكون بخير.
Do you feel that your listening is getting better
هل تشعر أن استماعك يتحسن؟
step by step?
خطوة بخطوة؟
I really hope so.
آمل ذلك حقا.
Trust me.
ثق بي.
This stage is all about practice, practice, practice.
هذه المرحلة كلها عن الممارسة، الممارسة، الممارسة.
Today's lesson is very useful
درس اليوم مفيد جدا
if you are traveling by plane.
إذا كنت تسافر بالطائرة.
We will practice the most important English words
سنمارس أهم الكلمات الإنجليزية
and phrases you need during a flight.
والعبارات التي تحتاجها أثناء الرحلة.
Maybe you are traveling for work
ربما تسافر للعمل
maybe you are traveling for tourism or to visit family.
ربما تسافر للسياحة أو لزيارة العائلة.
Being on a plane can sometimes make you nervous
التواجد على متن طائرة قد يجعلك أحيانا تشعر بالتوتر
if you don't understand English well,
إذا لم تفهم الإنجليزية جيدا،
especially when the flight attendants speak fast
خصوصا عندما تتحدث المضيفات بسرعة
or when the pilot makes announcements.
أو عندما يعلن الطيار عن ذلك.
But don't worry.
لكن لا تقلق.
With practice, it will become easier and easier.
مع الممارسة، سيصبح الأمر أسهل وأسهل.
You will feel more confident.
ستشعر بثقة أكبر.
You will understand more.
ستفهم أكثر.
In this video, I will tell you a short, simple story
في هذا الفيديو، سأحكي لكم قصة قصيرة وبسيطة
about being on a plane.
عن كوني على متن طائرة.
You will hear real-life common English phrases.
ستسمع عبارات إنجليزية شائعة في الحياة الواقعية.
I will speak slowly and clearly
سأتحدث ببطء ووضوح
so you can follow easily.
لذا يمكنك المتابعة بسهولة.
If you want, you can repeat after me.
إذا أردت، يمكنك التكرار بعدي.
This is a good way to improve both
هذه طريقة جيدة لتحسين الاثنين
your listening and speaking
استماعك وتحدثك
Are you ready?
هل أنت مستعد؟
Let's go.
هيا بنا.